<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Aleksi Tarvainen</title>
    <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Aleksi Tarvainen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.atarv.dev/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaalikartta</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/vaalikartta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/vaalikartta/</guid>
      <description>Vaalikartta is a web app to explore data about Finnish parliamentary elections from 1983 to 2019. It also includes some information about each municipality and cabinets.
It is a product of the course Open Data Student Projects (TIEA207). We developed the app in a group of four students. I took care of extracting most of the data and developing the backend API. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have any designated project manager, but our project board was managed mostly by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/homepage/</guid>
      <description>I started working on this site on 2019-09-04. The site is built with Hugo using its various functionalities (eg. templates). The theme is my homebrew. I call it minimus for being minimal (although barebones would describe it equally well).
As a side note, Hugo is based on the Go programming language, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t particularly used at all, but it seemed the best alternative of the static site generators I know of (Jekyll, Hakyll, Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPG-Dice</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/rpg-dice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/rpg-dice/</guid>
      <description>I built this little app, when I was working on Helsinki university&amp;rsquo;s Fullstack MOOC 2019. I wanted to try out how Typescript pairs with React. Maybe Typescripts best parts wont&amp;rsquo;t show, when making such small apps, but I saw it&amp;rsquo;s potential. Defining types gives me a sense of safety and I much prefer compilation errors to runtime errors, which really don&amp;rsquo;t hint at eg. what could cause something to be undefined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>