<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Aleksi Tarvainen</title>
    <link>https://www.atarv.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Aleksi Tarvainen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:12:56 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.atarv.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>M.net listings aggregator</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/mnet-aggregator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:12:56 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/mnet-aggregator/</guid>
      <description>Goal At some point this summer I noticed that I spend too much time browsing through listings on Muusikoiden.net&amp;rsquo;s tori (a Finnish marketplace for used music gear). Of course, as a programmer the first thing that comes to mind is automate things, so I did. The goal was to develop a program that scrapes new listings from the site and sends a daily summary of them via email.
Development process I started by looking at what web scraping libraries were available for Haskell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chargen</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/chargen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:16:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/chargen/</guid>
      <description>I built this OSRIC™ compatible random character generator, not because there isn&amp;rsquo;t one or another already, but because none of them is my own 😁. It is a bit limited right now, because it only generates characters&#39; attributes, alignments, class-race combinations and randomized levels. Maybe I will extend it by making generation of names, items, small descriptions and such possible in the future.
I wrote the back-end in Haskell and front-end in Elm, which both are functional programming languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A December of Algorithms 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/posts/a-december-of-algorithms-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/posts/a-december-of-algorithms-2019/</guid>
      <description>What? A December of Algorithms 2019 was an open coding challenge organized by SVCE-ACM student chapter. For each day of the month they presented a small algorithmic programming problem. Solutions to all of the problems had to be submitted by 2020-01-10.
Why? The holidays were approaching and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d need something to keep my little gray programming brain cells active. I was aware of Advent of Code, but I decided to do this challenge instead, because I considered it to be more approachable and doable, for sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaalikartta</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/vaalikartta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/vaalikartta/</guid>
      <description>Vaalikartta is a web app to explore data about Finnish parliamentary elections from 1983 to 2019. It also includes some information about each municipality and cabinets.
It is a product of the course Open Data Student Projects (TIEA207). We developed the app in a group of four students. I took care of extracting most of the data and developing the back-end API. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have any designated project manager, but our project board was managed mostly by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/homepage/</guid>
      <description>I started working on this site on 2019-09-04. The site is built with Hugo using its various functionalities (e.g. templates). The theme is my home brew. I call it minimus for being minimal (although bare-bones would describe it equally well).
As a side note, Hugo is based on the Go programming language, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t particularly used at all, but it seemed the best alternative of the static site generators I know of (Jekyll, Hakyll, Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPG-Dice</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/rpg-dice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/projects/rpg-dice/</guid>
      <description>I built this little app, when I was working on Helsinki university&amp;rsquo;s Fullstack MOOC 2019. I wanted to try out how Typescript pairs with React. Maybe Typescripts best parts wont&amp;rsquo;t show, when making such small apps, but I saw it&amp;rsquo;s potential. Defining types gives me a sense of safety and I much prefer compilation errors to runtime errors, which really don&amp;rsquo;t hint at eg. what could cause something to be undefined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://www.atarv.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.atarv.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I&amp;rsquo;m a fifth-year student at University of Jyväskylä majoring in mathematical information technology. I&amp;rsquo;m driven about doing robust and maintainable code - building software that matters. That has lead me to explore topics like functional programming and best practices of software development.
Regarding my musical endeavors, I&amp;rsquo;m part of the band This Horse. I dabble with making music solo (too), but I haven&amp;rsquo;t dared to put out anything yet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
